TYLER SPENCER

tspencer029@gmail.com 027 827 9081 https://www.linkedin.com/in/tyler-spencer-1a734713b/ https://github.com/tspencer029

CAREER STATEMENT

I am a highly motivated professional, with a BA and several years' experience working. I am currently studying towards my Masters of software development and I am looking for an internship in March 2018. I am passionate about learning and I am particularly interested in web and mobile app development, as well as building secure websites and applications. In my spare time I enjoy photography and going for walks in the outdoors.

EDUCATION

Victoria University

2018 Master of Software Development

Victoria University

2015 Bachelor of Arts in Political Science and Film

New Plymouth Boys' High School

EXPERIENCE

McDonald's | Courtenay Place

Crew Member April 2017 - Ongoing

Working in a team where everybody's part was very important to the smooth running of the restaurant. Attention to detail and maintaining professional standards.

Neil Mackenzie Photography | Wellington

Event Photographer June 2015 – September 2017

In this role it was very important to be reliable as it would be very difficult to find a replacement with the same skills at short notice. Communicated with students and staff to ensure that their needs were met. Gained significant experience using camera and lighting equipment as well as photo booths and computer systems.

Terrace Conference Centre | Wellington

Conference Assistant July 2016 – April 2017

Facilitating an enjoyable customer experience by ensuring that each conference room was clean and set up correctly for the following day. Washing the dishes and cleaning the kitchen after the conferences that were on during the day had concluded.

New World Island Bay | Wellington

Supermarket Associate February 2016 – December 2016

Worked mainly in the cold foods department providing assistance and information to customers, communicating with staff and shareholders to achieve customer satisfaction. Ensuring that food safety procedures were adhered to as well as occupational safety procedures.

Victoria University | Wellington

Kiwi Mate February 2015 – November 2015

Lived with international students and facilitated a smooth integration for them into life in New Zealand, both socially and academically. Communicated with domestic and international students from a variety of cultural backgrounds. Provided dispute resolution and management between individuals.

SKILLS

- Java Programming
 - Worked on numerous in class projects in Java including creating Conway's Game of Life in Java
- SQLite Databases
 - Worked on SQL and SQLite databases in class and in projects as well as real-time databases like Google Firebase
- HTML and CSS
 - Created websites in class including a custom burger ordering website. Currently working on creating personal websites for my software development and photography which is an ongoing project
- JavaScript
 - Created a website for the burger ordering project that was populated by JavaScript to display burger to a staff interface as they arrived
- Adobe Photoshop, Lightroom and Premiere
 - Frequent use of Adobe Photoshop and Lightroom for my photography and class projects as well as Premiere for video editing
- Team Work
 - Worked in a team at University and in many of my previous jobs
- Professional Standards
- Communication
- Attention to detail

INTERESTS

- Photography
- Filmmaking
- Website building
- Cyber security
- Machine Learning
- Travel and travel writing
- Hiking and walking

References available on request.